PROFESSOR: I like the answer.
It's infinite.
OK, I told you what the
search tree is.
It is where you currently are at the
root, and then everything that could
possibly happen in response to a plan.
Well, one plan is to go to A. Another
plan is to go to B. If I went to A,
there's this plan of going to B. If I
went to B, there's a plan of going to
A.
I guess I could also go to the goal.
Maybe that would be smart.
But then from B, I can go to A. And I
can go to B, and this just continues.
OK, so I took this nice little
graph, and I just said, OK,
this graph is so big.
Let's replace it with a tree.
And OK, it went from being
four states to infinite.
What the heck am I trying
to pull here?
OK, in order to come up with efficient
algorithms, one, we're not going to
use the whole infinite tree or we're
in trouble, and two, eventually,
although it won't be until next lecture,
we're going to get rid of a
lot of this repetition in the tree.
And in particular, there's a lot of
repeated structure in the search tree.
And we will have ways of dealing with
that, but today, repeated structure in
the search tree is just going
to be repeated work.
It'll be OK.
We'll fix it next time.